# Hariprasad Hanamkonda

hariprasadhnk493@gmail.com

9505089595

# Summary

DevOps Engineer, with Overall 7 years of experience with demonstrated skills and 4 years of hands-on experience in AWS cloud, and DevOps tools such as Kubernetes, Git, Jenkins, Maven, Tomcat, Docker, Terraform and programming knowledge in Shell scripting.

# **Experience**



### DevOps Engineer

Wipro Limited

May 2020 - Present (3 years 9 months)

- As a Devops engineer Launching Amazon EC2 Cloud Instances using Amazon Web Services (Linux/ Ubuntu) and Configuring launched instances with respect to specific applications
- Working on Multiple AWS instances, set the security groups, Elastic Load Balancer and AMIs, Auto scaling. Created and Maintained Git repositories, branches and tags.
- Setup Jenkins and created jobs for different builds. Launching Amazon EC2 Cloud Instances using Amazon Web Services (Linux/ Ubuntu) and Configuring launched instances with respect to specific applications
- Working on Multiple AWS instances, set the security groups, Elastic Load Balancer and AMIs, Auto scaling.
- Created and Maintained Git repositories, branches and tags. Setup Jenkins and created jobs for different builds.

# Senior Process Executive-Data

Cognizant

Apr 2018 - Apr 2020 (2 years 1 month)

- I Worked as a senior process executive-Data Cloud over 2 years from 2018-2020.
- Whereas Launching Amazon EC2 Cloud Instances using Amazon Web Services (Linux/ Ubuntu) and Configuring launched instances with respect to specific applications Working on Multiple
- AWS instances, set the security groups, Elastic Load Balancer and AMIs, Auto scaling. Created and Maintained Git repositories, branches and tags.
- Launching Amazon EC2 Cloud Instances using Amazon Web Services (Linux/ Ubuntu) and Configuring launched instances with respect to specific applications.
- Working on Multiple AWS instances.



#### Senior Associate

#### Wipro Limited

Mar 2017 - Mar 2018 (1 year 1 month)

- I worked for Wipro technologies as an Associate for over 1 year from 2017-18 in a quality environment where my knowledge was shared, enriched, and exposed my skills for the growth of the company.
- As I started my career in the Company, I have learned teamwork and problem- solving and based upon my performance I have promoted to critical levels in the process and I have received RNRs.
- I was a POC Of the project and lead for the employee Wellbeing and Apart of ideation team.
- Personal attributes include a dedication to a job with strong loyalty. However, an individual will act as a part of the team and analyse rapidly to react the problematic situations.
- I have achieved good knowledge on various roles of given projects and design Great numerical and analytical skills
- Skilled on Data visualisation and Conduct complex data analysis and report on results .
- Evaluate business needs and objective.

#### **Education**



#### 🥘 Vaagdevi College of Engineering

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Computer Science and Engineering 2012 - 2016

#### State Board of Intermediate Education

MPC, Mathematics Physics Chemistry Apr 2010 - Jun 2012

#### Vaagdevi high school

SSC

#### Skills

Cloud • Linux • Ubuntu • Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD) • Git • Maven • Shell Scripting • docker • DevOps • Kubernetes